ASHLEY COWAN

Inspired outcomes from great plans and systems

A Chartered
Accountant with
over 13 years'
private sector,
government and
not-for-profit
experience, I enjoy
improving controls,
efficiencies and
business outcomes

QUALIFICATIONS

Member of the Institute of Chartered Accountants in Australia (CA)

Bachelor of Science (Major: Mathematics) The University of Sydney

Bachelor of Commerce (Double Major: Finance and Economics) The University of Sydney

ABOUT

I am passionate about numbers and controls and how I can make them work for organisations.

I enjoy solving financial and systemic challenges and seeing businesses benefit from my expertise.

My experience includes conducting and supervising audit and assurance engagements for public and private clients.

My key skills include the conduct of investigative site visits, control reviews and succinct presentations to senior stakeholders.

Deliverables I produce include Internal Audit Reports, Enterprise Risk Management Frameworks, Risk Registers and assurance advice.

WORKING WITH SIMILAR ORGANISATIONS

Across my career I have provided internal audit, external audit, assurance and risk management services to a number of clients. My education sector clients include the Office of the NSW Board of Studies, Catholic Education Office and TAFE Directors Australia.

My not-for-profit and State and Federal government experience includes Baptistcare NSW and ACT, Legal Aid NSW, Special Broadcasting Services (SBS), NSW Ageing Disability and Home Care, Racing NSW, WorkCover Authority of NSW, NSW Electoral Commission, Office of the Protective Commissioner and Public Guardian, NSW Department of Justice and the Attorney General, Department of Finance and Services, Sydney Ferries and Office of State Revenue.

ASHLEY COWAN

Enabling efficiency and effectiveness.

INTERESTS

Outside of work I have a keen interest in sports, particularly cricket where I captain 4th grade for Sydney University.

I also play soccer and golf in the winter months.







EMPLOYMENT

2014 – 2021	MANAGER – AUDIT AND ASSURANCE WALTER ALLAN HALL
2013 - 2014	SENIOR AUDITOR MOORE STEPHENS
2011 – 2012	SENIOR AUDITOR HILL ROGERS SPENCER STEER
2010 - 2011	SENIOR CONSULTANT PWC

REFERENCES

Available on request